this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC Radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
softball all zero is the easiest and
fastest way to implement authentication
and authorization architectures into
your apps and ap is allow your users to
login with username and password social
and enterprise identity providers such
as Facebook Twitter ad or office 365 or
without passwords using slack or
whatsapp getting started is very easy
use one of more than 40 SDKs and add a
few lines of code no credit card
required get the free plan at auth0 dot
io / SC radio that's a you th the number
0 io / SE radio asura was trusted by
developers at Atlassian Mozilla
Optimizely in financial times try it out
at our zero dot io / se radio and get
back time building core features hello
this is Matthew Farwell for software
engineering radio today's episode is
about managing secrets with Armand Agha
Armand is the CTO of a Shi Corp where he
brings distributed systems to the world
of DevOps tooling he has worked on nomad
volt terraform console and surfer Joshi
Corp Armen welcome to software
engineering radio thanks so much Matthew
for having me as research fellows
episode I was actually going through the
back catalogue of software engineering
radio and we've covered quite a few of
the hash she called products in the past
for instance episode 264 James Philips
on service discovery which covered
console episode 289 James Turnbull on
declarative programming which covered
terraform and of course in 2014
episode 2:07 with Mitchell Hashimoto on
the vagrant project so at least Hasek
old product seems to be popular at least
on this podcast today we're going to
talk about secrets management so I think
we'll need to start with a few
definitions so what is a secret
sure yeah I think this is a you know I
think the whole space around secret
management is it's kind of a new and
emerging set of definitions and you know
the way we like to describe it is really
you know let's be very clear about what
we consider a piece of secret
information versus what we consider sort
of merely sensitive and the the kind of
definitions we like to use is anything
that we that can be used authenticate or
authorize is what we consider a secret
so just to make that concrete a username
and password is secret because I can use
it to actually log into a system and
then similarly if I have you know an API
token I can use that to make a request
to an API service and that token grants
me the right level of authentication and
authorization to make a request and sort
of then the the kind of 3rd category
something maybe like a an SSL
certificate or a TLS certificate where
by presenting this to another
counterparty I'm proving my identity
which then is allowing me to sort of be
authenticated or authorized and so those
kind of things anything that kind of is
granting me access to a system or
elevating my access to a system is what
we consider a secret so we specifically
we're not talking about things like a
key pass or password safe or one
password so those kind of systems will
typically hold on to a secret
information as well so if I'm using
something like one password it's holding
on to you know usernames and passwords
and API tokens as well which are which
are secret the kind of space that we're
in is really more about how do we think
about secret management for sort of our
applications so I have a web service
that needs to talk to a database or I
have an API service that needs to talk
to Amazon and so a system like that
won't be able to log into an interactive
application like one password right so
one passwords really a lot more you know
that class of tool is a lot more suited
for me and end-user on my personal
laptop and less suited for an
application running in a data center ok
so why does systems need secrets that's
a great question
you know it really comes down to you
know what is the security posture we
want to take within our data centers and
I think you know in some sense there's
there's a reason why we didn't talk
about these kinds of systems a few years
ago which was the assumption used to be
if I have an app running in my data
center you know it's running on a
private network and that private network
is secure and so you know yes my
database needs you know a username and
password to connect to it but I'll just
use the default
you know root root for the database and
I'll just hard code that in my
application to connect the database with
root root and you know I think what
we've seen increasingly over the last
few years is that's a bad assumption the
assumption that our network is you know
somehow perfectly secure you know
anytime we open up the news it's almost
like a weekly basis it's like you know
what was the latest company to get
hacked and so that's really what's
driving this is the sort of mentality
shift to say actually my network isn't
secure and at some point there's gonna
be a bug in my application or my
operating system or some piece of
middleware that I depend on that's gonna
get let an attacker get on my network
and so you know maybe my database
password shouldn't be you know root root
so what is secrets management yeah so
secret management that's a great
question is acknowledging okay if we
have this class of secrets right
database credentials and API tokens and
and sort of certificates how do we
manage them right and when we say
management we really mean kind of a few
things which is how are we distributing
that secret to the end application so I
have a web server it needs to talk to a
database so therefore it needs the
username and password of the database
how do I actually get that password to
that to the web server how do I update
that thing so you know a sort of good
practice and security is you know
credentials should not last forever so I
don't want my database password to be
the same thing until the end of time so
how do I update that but then make sure
my web server actually gets an
appropriately updated password so I can
connect to the database and then sort of
the flipside is suppose we do get
breached suppose there is a compromised
an attacker gets on our network or gets
to our database
how do we revoke that secret how do we
update it how do we sort of react if
there is a compromise and so those kind
of questions answering those questions
and building a process around that is
really what secret management is so why
why do we need to share the secrets you
said we need to share the secrets
between the server so imagine we I've
got five web servers which are logging
into one single database yep why do I
need to share secrets between those
things yeah why can't I just have five
logins you you can't you can have five
logins but the question becomes you know
how does the webserver actually get the
username and password to connect to the
database and that is sort of the core
heart of secret management so my web
server boots where does it get this does
it get the username and password just
from a configuration file and if it gets
it from a configuration file you know
how did that secret get there did I you
know did a did a human operator manually
ssh into the machine and populate the
username and password for the web server
or was it driven by you know was it just
hard-coded in plaintext and now if i'm
able to access any of the machines i can
just see what the username and password
is on disk or if that file is stored in
you know in github and plaintext i can
just access github and see what the
database credentials are and so in some
sense that the surface area of access is
too wide anyone could see these these
credentials
why is secrets management hard you know
I think yeah that's a great question why
is it hard you know the challenge of it
becomes you know I think it's even
bigger than just secret management it
kind of speaks to the challenge of
security which is you know when we're
solving many problems we can think about
the problem in kind of this localized
way we can think about okay I just care
about you know this performance problem
of one application right and I can
profile that and understand where the
bottleneck is and fix it in this very
isolated place security has the opposite
problem which is it's incredibly
holistic right if I'm an attacker who
says I want to break into this company
or there's data I want to exfiltrate I'm
not gonna figure out you know what's the
most secure part of that application
let me go attack that I'm gonna say let
me find any weakness in the system and
exploit that and so the mentality flips
we're all of a sudden it's not about
this how do I identify this very
localized problem and fix that it
becomes a holistic understanding of what
is my security story look like end to
end because security flows like water it
finds the path of least resistance and
so the challenge with secret management
is how do you think about you know the
life cycle of a secret let's say a
username and password from your database
and the whole life cycle of where does
the secret get defined where does it get
stored who has access to it how do I
distribute that secret to the web
servers and the API is and the humans
who need access to it and thinking about
that entire lifecycle chain in a way
where you say ok you know at no point
can the answer be the password is in
plain text and it can't be that anyone
can access it right because all of a
sudden and at any of those steps that is
true that's where the attacker is going
to get to it it's not going to be within
the encrypted part of the system it's
going to be within the plaintext part of
the system ok so even if I encrypt it on
the if I'm entering in my new Bolivar
SSH
it's still entered in plaintext in the
configuration file for instance correct
right ok are there different categories
of Secrets oh that's interesting
so like within secrets themselves I mean
I'm sure certainly their secrets that
are more sensitive than others and
there's different types of Secrets so
you know a few that we gave an example
of might be you know username and
password versus API token versus SSL
credential but then the question becomes
what do those systems give you access to
you know so I might have a username and
password that gives me read-only access
to a database that that sort of secret
is less sensitive than you know the
username and password that gives me root
access to a system and so there's
different levels of sort of severity I
guess associated with them and then many
different types of secret material do
they change over time ideally so this is
you know a big philosophical point for
us
is this notion that
you know historically the way secrets
were thought about was purely in the you
know we need a central place to kind of
you know in quotes vault the secrets
where we just need to put the secrets in
there and it's a static username and
password and that username password
never changes but it's encrypted in this
one central place and then applications
that need it can pull it out of the
central place and users who need it can
pull it out of the central place but
it's not changing and our view is you
know it ignores the problem that sure
okay it's super secure within that
central vault but the moment you know
Alice or Bob pull it out of the the
system they're like yeah it's sort of
annoying to have to go to the central
thing I'm just gonna put it on on my
desktop as a you know and a text file
that says you know here's the database
password so I don't have to bother go
talk to the vault or I'm gonna write it
on a sticky note and in the case of an
application the applications oftentimes
do a terrible job you know keeping
anything secret they'll end up logging
it out to their logs or they'll be
connected to new relic and new relic
will suck it up as an environment
variable and it's available there or you
know the system will have a trace back
and it prints it as part of the debug
screens like here's the database
username and password and so you know
it's kind of like you know if you've
ever told a secret to a friend you know
most people do a terrible job keeping a
secret right it's like before you know
it it kind of proliferate everywhere and
applications are sort of even worse they
tend to leak it everywhere so this kind
of gets to our philosophy of if secrets
aren't changing all the time they're not
secret for very long wait like you have
to assume at some point either an
application or a human is exposing it to
a system that's not properly encrypting
it not properly access controlling it
and it you know you have to assume it's
not not really privileged so our view is
how do we actually get to a place where
secrets are very ephemeral right think
almost like a one-time password type
thing which is like every time I'm
logging into a database it should be a
new randomly generated password kind of
like a 2fa code right I should get a new
pin every time so that even if I write
that pin on a piece of paper or I leak
it in a log file that it's invalid the
next time around you try and use it and
so in an ideal world the secrets should
be changing all the time you said to FA
just could you clarify what
means sorry two-factor authentication so
like any of any time you log in it sends
you like a text message or use like
Google Authenticator okay so does that
mean we need to think about secrets
which change quickly
oh and secrets that change slowly
because it seems to me there's there's
different uses use cases for both
totally totally you know so one of the
things we talked about within volt is we
introduced this idea of a dynamic secret
so of course there's gonna be all sorts
of static secrets that you know I put in
the username and password and that
username and password doesn't really
change until I manually you know change
it and come in and update vault could
you give an example of that of the use
of something like that
sure a perfect example sort of a static
secret might be my you know the the log
into my laptop as an example right the
first time I set it up I say you know
username Arman password one two three
four and until such time as I come in
and you know change my password and
update it it's gonna stay static it's
gonna be the same thing versus you know
we have this notion of a dynamic secret
where every time I request access to a
system the system will generate a new
dynamic one for me so here's an example
of it as you know and I might have a
database within my organization you know
it's my my sequel server and instead of
mice you know username and password
always being the same thing I go and I
talk to vault and say hey I need a you
know a read-only credential to the my
sequel or I need a a read/write
credential to my sequel server volt then
goes back and talks to my sequel and
generates a dynamic username and a
dynamic password that's specific to that
one request and hands it back to me it
says here you go here's your username
and password and by the way it's only
valid for the next 24 hours
and so 24 hours later vault talks to my
sequel and deletes that credential and
so in that sort of an interaction every
time I'm talking to the database or
every time I request a credential I get
a different one back and so that I think
is sort of that 2 speed mode where it's
like yeah there's a set of static you
know very slow changing things things
like my personal login to my laptop but
how do we move away from from that model
to one where you know per request or per
24 hours it's a different secret
another example of a secret which
doesn't change particularly rapidly
would be something like a backup so if
you're encrypting your backups right you
wouldn't want to change that secret very
often I would imagine right yeah that's
a great example and something you might
want to do with the backup is maybe
you're sharing the same let's call it
you know you assign a password that's
encrypting the backup that password you
know might be actually protecting a
different set of encryption keys each
time so every day when the backup takes
place how do instead of sharing maybe at
the same encryption key every single day
can each backup be encrypted with a
different key and then that the
underlying encryption key could be
protected by one the same password right
so this is kind of like a one password
or key pass type thing which is you know
I only have to remember that kind of one
password but it's being encrypted it was
sort of a different set of values each
time and that way you can you generates
key exactly exactly
okay using a pass okay that's fine
how does an application get hold of a
secret in a secrets management system
that's a great great question and that
is I think in some sense the crux of the
challenge you know it's this problem
called you know it's it's sort of the
secret zero problem or the bootstrapping
problem which is I'm a web server I just
boot up how do I now get access to to
the secrets I need how do I prove that
I'm a web server and select you know
you'll see that referred to by a few
different names which is you know
bootstrapping or secret zero or sort of
the last mile problem of secret
management which is the central vault
has two high is that somehow establish
trust with the client who's requesting
these secrets so you know to pull that
back then one level further effectively
you know one way to think about it is
kind of like a web of trust right which
is you know think about how a new
employee maybe starts at a company which
is you have an existing set of employees
who are trusted they already have you
know their username and password to log
in and the first day they show up you
know a chars like great you know welcome
to the company Alice your username is
Alice and you know here's your temporary
password you know one two three four
five the first time you're going to
again you're gonna be prompted to to
reset it and so that sort of onboarding
flow you know the day before Alice was
not trusted she was not a member of the
organization and so she had no access to
any of the internal systems but then
upon starting she was sort of securely
introduced to the company right they
sort of looked at her ID card they
looked at her you know letter of
employment that's that okay Alice should
be starting it matches her ID and she
looks the same as she looks like in her
driver's license great here's your using
a password welcome to the company and
you know that is sort of analogous to
what's happening with the applications
which is in some sense you tie into the
process of booting that web server and
so when the web server comes in there's
sort of a provisioning process so maybe
you're connecting to Amazon and saying
you know boot me a new VM and it should
be you know a web server and then you
know the way you'll tie that back into
these systems is kind of the same way HR
does the onboarding which is they'll
take great okay we know there should be
a web server booting you appear to be a
web server and you know you look like
the VM Amazon said it was gonna boot you
know welcome to the organization here's
the secrets for for being a web server
so it's sort of a very similar process
you're kind of extending this web of
trust from a set of systems that you
trust into this new thing that matches
you know it looks like something you
should be trusting imagine that for my
web server with five different servers
and one single database I want to
introduce a more formal or more secure
secrets management system into my
product given given the constraints that
we just talked about I guess we should
start with some sort of threat modeling
yeah that's a great point that's a great
point you know when we talk about the
threat modeling around secret management
there's really two classes of threats
one is sort of the sort of the obvious
one is sort of external threat these are
people who people are applications who
should have no access at all right
they're sort of malicious attackers or
outsiders and the threat model for them
is they should have no access to
anything ever
basically and then you have the second
class which was actually the much more
challenging one which is the insiders
right so these are people or
applications that should have access to
the system but only access to like the
relevant subset of information they need
so the web server should have access to
you know only the credentials it needs
to be a web service whether it's the
database password only and then you
might have an API server that needs
access to both the database and let's
say an Amazon API token and so the
internal threat is slightly different
which is how do we prove you are who you
say you are and that we scoped what you
have access to only what's relevant for
you versus an outsider is much simpler
which is you should just have no access
to anything ever so with that I don't
really want to go into the threat
modeling too deeply but what sort of
threats can good secret management help
us with that's a good question so what
it really comes down to is you know when
we talk about security there's kind of
three problems really are three sort of
works workflows we have to think about
one is how do we prevent a sort of an
attack from happening prevent a
compromise from happening it's sort of
step one right and an ounce of
prevention is worth a pound of cure and
really what that comes down to is saying
let's not you know let's try and make
things as secure as possible and
restrict access to to kind of a
need-to-know basis
but inevitably breaches happen no
security is perfect right know sort of
authorization miles perfect so then the
second class of concern becomes okay how
do I detect it when something goes wrong
so my prevention has failed now I need
to have a good story around how I detect
that a breach has happened and what data
was accessed and you know who what where
when and why is sort of the questions we
want to be able to answer and then that
last category is how do we mitigate it
right so now we've you know we try to
prevent that we failed we detected it
and we know sort of what is the surface
area of access and compromise and now
what do we do about it and that's the
mitigation and so if we have a good
story around us and we do our threat
modeling right then we can answer kind
of these three class of questions which
is okay have we done everything possible
to prevent it and scoped down the access
to just need to know the web server only
has access to the one database the API
only has access to the things that needs
so on and so forth
then from the detection have we done the
proper work in terms of audit logging
capability so that if that credential
gets leaked and our web servers hacked
we can see you know what's what are all
the secrets that were accessed that
maybe shouldn't have been and then sort
of the final bit is do we understand
what needs to be done to mitigate this
attack so do we know how we would change
the database password do we know how we
would you know change out the user name
and password you know block access to to
future things so on and so forth how we
want to react and so if we do a good job
with the threat modeling we have a good
answer for all three of these categories
it's not just a debt the secrets that
could be stolen as well it could be
sensitive data correct as well so
sensitive data being things like credit
card numbers socialite social security
numbers that sort of thing exactly and
that's an important distinction we make
is between sort of secret data which is
giving you access to things right so
authorizing or authenticating and then
the sensitive data which is protected by
it
so once you've breached sort of the
secret and you have access to to sort of
a credential you shouldn't that's what's
letting you trap into all that sensitive
information so it would be nice to know
what that person had access to at the
Pearl at the point where they were the
data was compromised right and how long
they had access for it and all those
kind of good questions okay so what are
some of the anti patterns of secret
management how much time do we have you
know I think the the probably the
biggest anti-pattern the biggest
anti-pattern I'd say is you know
probably there's two or three of them
one is you know what we refer to as
secret sprawl right and secret sprawl is
where secrets are just defined
everywhere right they're hard-coded in
the application they're in plain text
and config files they're in github
they're sort of littered in our
configuration management they're in
Dropbox and a wiki so on and so forth
there's the sort of extreme
decentralization and actually I
shouldn't even use likes the word
extreme it's it's so common that you
could hardly consider it extreme and the
challenge with something like that is
you can't really answer any of the hard
quad
which is who had access to the secret
right you know when it's in 15 different
systems and most of them are globally
readable you know the answer might be
every user at the company every you know
application anyone on the network and so
the answer ends up becoming all - every
question and so then you go to the next
question it's like okay everyone had
access and now there's been a breach
well where did that breach happen well
there's no way there's no audit logs
because it's in 15 different systems
right and the secret never changes so
did they access the secret yesterday or
two years ago and then just decided to
wait until today to use it right without
that sort of audit trail it is very hard
to reverse back you know what happened
and so that's sort of the detection
question and then you get to prevention
and say okay well now what do we do
about it
well it's defined in 15 different
systems in plain text all over the place
so there's not much you can't do
together and so that's probably the
number one the number one anti-pattern
is probably this decentralisation so
even if we had centralized even if it
was still in plaintext
right and we didn't do access control
and we didn't do a sort of any of the
other good things but we said actually
it's only defining this one place at
least in our answers get slightly better
to these other questions which is okay
well we know it must have come from this
place maybe there's web server logs from
that one system that we can access if we
need to change the password we only have
to change it in one place and not 15 and
so you know it's not a great story but
it's at least a vastly better story than
sort of the the sprawl that we normally
see so just before we moved on to the
second couple of anti-patterns I have a
question is does a good centralized
configuration management tools such as
zookeeper 80 CD or console help with
secrets management you know it improves
the situation let's put it that way I
wouldn't say you know there's there's
the good bad and the ugly you know that
moves us from maybe the ugly to the bad
we're at least now we have that sort of
centrality but when we look at systems
like zookeeper or at CD or console you
know none of them are really designed
with secrets in mind so they're not
they're not worried about encrypting of
the secrets they're not worried about
sort of fine grained access control and
auditing because they're assuming that
they're being used for much less
sensitive information
okay sorry just about after that aside
can we go back to the anti-patterns sure
sure yeah so if if sort of the
decentralization is it's kind of the
worst offender probably the number two
would be keeping things in plain text
you know even if we move things to being
centralized the problem is still if
we're not encrypting these secrets then
it's really still hard to answer some of
these questions in a very fine way right
if if it's in plain text everywhere then
really we've decoupled kind of the once
I've given it away or once I've written
a two-disc or written it to the wire I
don't have a strong assurance of you
know did it did it get stored in some
other system right versus if we're
encrypting all of these secrets then
really only the key holders are the ones
who could ever decrypt it right and
those become a much tighter set of
people it's much more controlled and
then you're not as worried of you know
if someone copied out this encrypted
value from the database it's sort of
like oh well right like unless you have
the encryption key it's just a
meaningless encrypted value to you
so that's probably like number two is
keeping things in plaintext in various
places but even with that you have the
key problem again
so if coming back to our if we're
putting the username and password for
the database we're encrypting it on the
on the web servers then that means that
the web servers have to have the
encryption key to be able to decrypt it
so it's still on the web servers well
ideally if we're doing sir seeker
management we have a central key holder
right so that the web servers are not
the sort of alt and the endpoint in
terms of where the decryption is
happening it's that the central kind of
key management solution of the central
secret management solution is encrypting
its own
and doing the decryption just in time
before handing it out to the client if
that makes okay so this is what they
call the trusted third party exactly so
we're sort of trusting the central
authority the central key management
system to do things properly but now we
move from a place where all of our web
servers have these encryption keys -
there's one system that we need to
secure and lock down right okay but the
web service still has to have access to
the correct the web server has to be
able to go talk in query out of that
system okay and the third button third
anti-pattern I think the third
anti-pattern you know I think this is
gonna be kind of almost a two-part
answer the third part anti-pattern is
sharing of credentials and those
credentials being long-lived right and
these things are sort of intertwined and
the reason I mean that is let's say I
have five web servers and all of them
are sharing the same username and
password forever right because it's
we're not changing them ever and you
know now we notice that our database is
compromised the question becomes okay
well which five of those systems and at
what time were they compromised and this
becomes a really hard question to answer
because there's a sharing of that same
value between all of the different
clients and they've been sharing it for
a very long time and so there's not a
good way of bounding the space or time
in which it was compromised and so
moving away from that and saying
actually you know and sort of the
analogy of that would be imagine if
every employee at a company had the
exact same login right you know it would
be very strange from an organizational
perspective because we'd it's almost
more obvious when it's people and you'd
say yeah obviously you know Alice Bob
and Charlie should have different
credentials so that we know who did what
but we don't necessarily think that way
when it comes to applications right
which is strange because they have the
same problem and so I think that sharing
becomes sort of that third anti-pattern
so what what you're saying is so each of
these web servers should have five
different usernames and passwords that's
a good thing to do anyway
right exactly okay and that they should
be forced to rotate as well in the same
way
we force people in an organization to
change their password every some number
of you know months or whatever okay and
the long-lived miss so the long-lived
Ness is sort of so once we've said okay
actually every web server is gonna have
a different password in some sense now
we've bounded space so you know if this
credential leaked we know it must be web
server five let's say that was
compromised but if it's been the same
password for five years
we don't know was it compromised last
week or five years ago and so then
getting into these shorter live
credentials lets us you know bound that
time so if the password changes you know
every day then we know you know on this
day is when the compromised took place
as opposed to sometime in the last five
years but you might not necessarily know
that the password has changed because
the auditing happens at the user level
name at the user level right and I think
this becomes a value of a good secret
management solution is that it should be
able to give you that sort of provenance
of you know what was the username and
password and at what time so that you
can sort of pinpoint that that sort of
you know where it was in terms of you
know what was the origin of the
compromised but what was the rough
timeline don't let security checks be a
burden on your software deployment
baracoa greenlight gives you secure
coding feedback in seconds directly in
your IDE try verrico hood greenlight for
eclipse free for 30 days and type in
devera codes binary static analysis
engine delivering in-depth and accurate
results to developers in just seconds
request your trial of greenlight for
eclipse today by visiting very code comm
/ greenlight - trial not using eclipse
visit very code comm slash greenlight
for information on Visual Studio and
IntelliJ plugins how do we update a
secret and how often should we do it
that's a great question you know I think
it really comes down to sort of this
tension between how good we get at
secret management right so I guess let
me start from sort of the Platonic ideal
the Platonic ideal would be every single
time that I connect to the database
let's just say it's a different password
because that is now the ideal
Aereo as i can say i can pinpoint down
to this exact interaction when this
happened right you know in some sense
that'd be kind of the same as you know
I'm gonna rekey my house every time I
open the door every time I get into my
house I'm reeking and I now I have a new
key you know it becomes very impractical
right and so there's a certain cost and
overhead associated with doing this so
the real world trade-off becomes sort of
finding that middle ground where you say
okay maybe rhe king every single time is
excessive and extreme and then it's
really about your risk tolerance right
do I want to do it daily do I want to do
it weekly do I want to do it monthly and
so there's no perfect answer it really
comes down to risk tolerance right if I
was you know managing nuclear launch
codes you know probably my risk
tolerance would be incredibly low and I
would you know I would make an effort to
to get those things you know you know
and in fact they do they're all one-time
passwords so they're quite literally
only usable one time for that reason
versus if I'm managing you know my
pantry I'm you know I'm probably not
putting a lock on it
how should I revoke a secret is this the
same process so revoking a secret super
interesting and I think really comes to
you know where we're seeing interest in
some of the more modern secret
management systems the challenge in the
past is if we're living in this world of
extreme decentralization and we really
don't think about sort of the challenges
in terms of updating then revocation can
be basically impossible right so if I
have my five web servers and all five of
them share a username and password then
you know if I know that password has now
leaked I can't go to the database and
just revoke it because all of a sudden
all five of the servers will get
disconnected at the same time so this
sharing is actually causing this problem
where you know if it was a severe enough
breach maybe we're okay with that we're
saying you know just take down the whole
service until we figure this out revoke
access from everything but if we really
want to be more fine-grained and say
actually we just want to revoke the
credential for this from the system that
we believed to have been compromised
you have to you know a prerequisite of
that
is that you're not doing a sharing and
that you have a centrality of management
that lets you actually do that because
if it's hard-coded in the application
you know there's not an easy way to to
recompile the application and provide
the new credential to it
so how much auditing do we need from our
secrets management tool ideally you know
everything right anything going in and
out would be auditable right and I think
this goes back to you know in the
general case we're not really looking at
it but when that breach happens we
really want to have as much of the
forensic information available to us as
possible so who did it when did they do
it where did they do it from you know
all of that information becomes super
useful and so the way we sort of think
about it as any request every request
should be audited so that you have that
full trail I need request to the secrets
management system or any request to the
database for instance at a minimum for
sure to the secret management system
every request and then you know if you
can you know again goes back to this
question of you know that data starts to
become huge after a while right in that
there's that similar sort of overhead of
if I have every access to my underlying
database system you know is that a
manageable amount of data and that
really ties back to your risk profile
which is like you know if it's the
nuclear launch codes probably audit
every one of those things then you know
pay Splunk a little more and this whole
ties back to the threat modeling as well
because it did you have to decide what
you want to protect and exactly which
bits exactly and this is I think the fun
nuance of security is that in some sense
and I you know I hope I don't seem like
I'm trying to dodge these questions but
you know security is so contextual
unlike something else where some of
these other areas you know there is a
best practice in terms of how security
you know service discovery should be
done as an example they're just like
here's the right way to do it right
where's security it's it's so dependent
on like what is your risk profile what
is the sort of cost of a mistake and the
right answer changes basically okay it's
this is kind of an open question if
given the choice between focusing on
secrets management or network or
application security where would you
draw the line
ooh you know my view is there sort of an
8020 rule with everything so when we
look at network security I think you
know the the end-all-be-all assumption
for a long time was we're gonna build
this network perimeter and then put you
know a single front door with and put
our firewall in our intrusion detection
and sort of all of our security at that
one point and a suit and basically
construct an impenetrable Network and
that was the assumption was that it's
the sort of castle and moat way of
looking at the world and the challenge
with that assumption becomes it was like
okay well what if what if they get it
right what if you know let's just play
that they can't hypothetical we've
invested so much energy on fortifying
the wall that the inside of the network
is completely soft and so the moment the
attacker is in it's game over
and so to me this becomes this and now
this sort of perfect experiment of like
that 8020 rule which is okay it's worth
building that Network perimeter for sure
and investing to that 80% of sort of the
defense but then assume they're gonna
get in and don't try and get that to a
hundred percent instead look at sort of
the next class of protection which is
okay if they're in then what if your
assumption is it's you know if when
they're in it's game over that's a bad
answer and that's where it makes sense
to invest in things like secret
management and get that to the 8020
percent rule right where you say okay
can we put in the investment an effort
so that you know we get our secret
management story to the eighty percent
mark of preventing sort of excessive
amount of access to things having
auditing having a revocation story and
similar with applications security is
how do we get to sort of 8020 on all
three of these defenses which are
independent defenses as opposed to let's
get one defense to a hundred percent and
if it fails game over so how is secrets
management chain talking of this how his
secrets management changed with move to
the cloud so you know in some sense the
move to the cloud has been you know I
think the the camel that broke the back
on the assumption that the network
perimeter was secure right I think we
held on to that assumption you know
longer than we should have in the
physical data center world because a
physical datacenter quite literally has
four walls in one door
and so there was the sort of more
convenient analogy to be made and it
sort of ignores the fact that we had
VPNs and multiple data centers connected
to one another and things like that but
as we move to cloud it becomes obvious a
cloud is nebulous there is no four walls
there is no front door and so that whole
analogy that whole way of thinking just
starts breaking down and it makes much
more clear that okay while we can sort
of put together you know a network
perimeter it's definitely not as sort of
robust as what we used to have and it
forces us to take that assumption that
at some point this network will be
breached and what should our posture be
how do we bring in secret management and
and not have the inside of the network
be completely soft okay so the idea is
to be as you say in the 80/20 rule for
application security secrets management
and network security right exactly again
okay
one of the other hosts Kim Carter does a
lot of work on security in it and in his
book the holistic info center for web
web developers one of the statistics
that he quotes is that 71 for particular
for health care providers 71% of all
attackers were carried out by insiders
some of which were malicious and some of
us were inadvertent how does that change
our approach to secrets management yeah
that's a great question and I think sort
of perfectly maps back into that sort of
challenge of the castle and moat
thinking which is you know if we only
think about the adversary as being an
external outsider then all we have to do
is build a really tall wall but the
moment we allow our threat model to
include well someone on the inside of
the wall could be malicious then it
really breaks down it doesn't matter how
tall the wall that's on the outside
anymore it really becomes about okay how
do you give the individuals on the
inside enough you know credentials that
they can do their job right we can't go
to a world where we say we're not going
to trust anybody and no one has access
to anything because otherwise it becomes
very hard to do do our actual work but
if I decide you know what I didn't get
the race I wanted I'm going to
you know I'm gonna become a malicious
actor how do I make sure that my blast
radius is limited to only the things
that I actually needed access to to do
my job and I think this perfectly
highlights that challenge of perfect
security is I might need access to the
database to do my normal job so I can't
be in a world where I just don't have
access to it but if I decide to be
malicious with that access that's when
we move from prevention to detection
because at that point there was no way
to prevent that I needed the access
fundamentally to do my job but I didn't
need to maybe exfiltrate the data and
you know share it and so you know I
think this does that this highlights you
know that 71% I think is totally
accurate right you know external attacks
are actually relatively rare compared to
the insider attacks and it highlights
that need to sort of bring secret
management in and invest not only in
prevention but also detection and
mitigation so should I be encrypting
everything yes for sure for sure
everything should be encrypted you know
I think even even my database
especially your database yeah I mean or
just the sensitive information in the
database yeah I mean I think if it's
truly you know non sensitive information
then then I guess you know it might not
be worth that investment but the way we
think about it is you know how upset are
you gonna be if this ends up on cnn.com
right like if this gets leaked to the
Internet are you gonna wish it was
encrypted or not right and if the answer
is like not really then okay maybe you
don't need to apply encryption but if
the answer is like yeah that would be a
bad day for us then it's probably a good
idea and I think the other you know it
comes back to that notion you know the
question you asked which is how much
should I invest in network security
versus you know network and app and
secret management and having these you
know what it comes down to is having
independent sort of failure domains
right so if I say I'm only investing in
network security and that thing fails
then it's game over right versus if I
have these three different layers of
defenses then even if one system fails I
have an opportunity to apply sort of
defense-in-depth with these other
systems encrypting the database is
similar if I say
you know what the username and password
protecting the database is the
end-all-be-all defense
what if someone who is an insider gets
access to it what if an attacker gets
access to it is it just game over versus
if great now you have access to the data
all that information you really care
about is encrypted this sort of second
factor this defense and death becomes
are you a key holder right or are you
authorized to go talk to you know a key
holding system to do decryption of that
data because if not now you have this
totally independent second factor that
also has to be breached okay I'd like to
move on to what some of the systems that
are available for secrets management
we've already mentioned vault but if I
go through if I look up on the Internet
Systems secrets management there are a
multitude era encrypted data bags in
chef chef volt Huayra aisle I am hasha
got volt cur with and that's just
ignoring the ones which are paid
solutions if I assume that I've decided
I don't want to roll my own secrets
manager how do I go about choosing a
secrets management tool that's a good
question I mean you know I'll be upfront
that clearly there's going to be some
vendor bias here right so - just in the
interest of transparency but you know I
think it comes down to understanding you
know a few things which is like what's
your environment look like right and
what are your what are sort of that what
are your needs from a secret management
system right and I think it's kind of
you know if you need the camry you know
getting the Ferrari might be overkill
and I think part of the challenge
becomes these different systems are
oftentimes built assuming a very
particular environment right and so you
know let's just takes Kiwis as an
example it was a internal project at
square that was spun out well the result
of that is it makes a lot of assumptions
about what the environment looks like
that are perfectly valid Foursquare
because it was built for their
environment and so it's all squares
problems in squares environment and so
if your problem looks the same and your
environment looks similar enough it
might be a great solution for you it
might be a great fit versus if you know
you look at a tool like Hasek or default
you know we
atul smith right so you know in some
sense we're not building it for ourself
we're building it for other people and
so our our sort of view going in is how
do we minimize the assumptions about
what the environment looks like and
support the broadest array of
environments and how do we support
everyone from you know hey it's a
two-person side project all the way to
you know we have fortune 20 customers
and so you know what our goals are not
necessarily the same goals as you know
key was in terms of supporting squares
needs so how do i how do I go about
authentica authenticating myself with
fault that's a great question and that
goes to that that sort of secure
bootstrap the sort of heart of that
question it's tied very intimately to
how you actually provision and deploy
applications so what I mean by that is
let's say I'm using you know Amazon and
I'm booting you know a VM and Amazon
volt Tizen and treats Amazon as a
trusted third party so you know the sort
of analogy to be made as when I started
out the company they trusted you know
the federal government to issue me a
driver's license that says this is Arman
and that's being used by HR to say you
know this you know yes you can join the
organization and in a similar case you
know when of vm boots and connects to
vaults as I'm the web server you know
we're looking at the identity document
provided by Amazon that says this
machine set is what it says it is and
we're saying great we trust Amazon to
have sort of done the cryptographic
identity correctly you're allowed in and
so the question becomes sort of you know
based on the platform you're running on
can we establish a chain of trust
between our system vault and the client
that's coming in and so you know we work
closely with Amazon and Google and
Microsoft and so on all the major kind
of cloud platforms to do that that's
sort of integration with them okay so
but that that's something you got to
think about with virtually any secrets
management or how do you integrate with
the environment with aw right that's for
instance exactly you have to establish
that sort of a chain of trust between
your secret management system and the
application and so that almost
invariably
there's some intermediary there and so
it really becomes a question of does the
tool integrate into that into the system
that you're using the environment that
you're using so this could be analogous
to pop it
so when puppet client first connects to
the puppet server the puppet server then
has to say yes I believe this puppet
client exactly identical problem okay
is it worth using voltar and indeed any
secrets management on a single machine
if we're not sharing the keys between
motor shoes that's an interesting
question I mean you know the reality
might be no it might be that it's
actually not worth it and you know so
let me sort of ground that just so that
if this doesn't get quoted out of
context I'm making a series of
assumptions here which is if our whole
application runs on one machine what is
the risk profile here
right and how big is the team that's
managing this thing right and is it
worth the cognitive overhead of learning
a secret management system deploying it
operating it if our risk profile is a
single machine and so I'm making a
number of assumptions in terms of you
know you know how sensitive this
application is and how big the team is
but you know very likely if it's only
one machine it's maybe a very very small
team and the risk profile is relatively
limited and it might not justify that
investment if it so happens that that
machine is securing you know millions of
dollars in transactions then yeah surely
the risk profile is high enough that
it's worth it but it's a it's a very
nuance to answer a very interesting
answer there's there's another use case
here is that you are creating software
which is deployed on a client site which
is a single machine Oh interesting okay
yeah so in that sort of an environment I
wouldn't think about it as a single
machine it's unless there's only one
client if there's many different client
sites that are all being sort of
centrally managed and provisioned then
really at that central point is where
you have the opportunity to say actually
these hundred client sites they have
independent credentials can be
naturally managed and reduces the the
surface area of access at risk okay so
to recap when people are starting to
think about secrets management in the
large like this what what are the first
three things that they should do first
three things they should do okay so the
first three things I would I would do is
kind of get get a handle on a few
different questions question one is what
are all of our secrets and where are
they
that's question 1 question 2 would be
you know which applications in which
people should have access to what
secrets right so figuring out you know
in some sense what is our trust model
here who needs access to what and then
question 3 is you know what's the
simplest path of getting all those
secrets to one place and making sure
that that access model that we just
defined in sort of question 2 is what's
enforced like that to me would be the 3
steps right because I think step one is
surprisingly hard because most
organizations are coming from a place of
decentralization it actually becomes a
whole process of discovery to understand
where are all these things defined are
they hard-coded in the app or in github
or where are they and so having that map
of here's where everything is here's who
should have access to to all of it and
then you know how do we actually get
there what's the path to to centralizing
and enforcing that access and should we
be thinking about the the three kinds of
threats that you're talking about the
prevention of compromised detection of
compromised and mitigation of
compromised totally and I think I think
again that follows sort of the 80/20
rule which is prevention is in some
sense 80% of it 80% of the value is the
prevention and so if you're starting
from a place of key sprawl and you know
that's kind of a the assumption that
these things are plaintext everywhere
you're gonna get the most bang from the
buck from just getting the the
prevention in place and then you know
the follow-on to that becomes sort of
the next highest value becomes you know
let's set up the audit logging
capability and have the ability to do
the the detection and forensics that we
need
and then sort of the final level of
maturity would be let's have a
well-defined
sort of mitigation strategy in place but
I think in terms of that 8020 80% of the
value is in getting the prevention going
and just enabling basic audit logging is
there anything else I should have asked
you you know I think one thing that we
like to talk about is you know secret
management in some sense is it's a
spectrum right it's it's not just a
binary so it's you know in terms of the
maturity curve of like where you could
be on it I'd be happy to chat a little
bit about okay even if we implement a
sort of central vaulting you know what's
next right like what are the next few
steps from there because I don't think
you're done okay and how can how can
people find out more about this subject
that's a great question I think it's
actually a developing area in many ways
I think you know that this assumption
shift from sort of the the soft interior
to to actually securing it as new so I
think there's limited material I mean
you know I think we have a lot of
documentation that we provide around the
vault project in some sense that doesn't
give you the sort of broader level view
of what is the challenge you know I
think if you go in onto YouTube and you
search sort of secret management you'll
see a number of good talks given either
by folks at Hasek or poor folks at
docker and a few other organizations who
have talked about what does modern
secret management really mean and I
think those are a great starting point
because they sort of lay out here's the
forest of challenges and let's just kind
of understand the landscape before
diving into the details
we had a Nessie radio interview with
Diego Monica on dhaka security which is
290 just for anybody who's interested in
that thank you for joining us today
Armen where can people find out more
about you I'm all over the internet is
just armand it turns out it's a yeah
yeah luckily there's a little little
name conflict so I'm on on Twitter as
Armand I'm a you know LinkedIn you know
you'll find me all about there I might
github as well okay
this is Matthew Farwell for software
engineering radio thank you for
listening
thanks so much Matthew don't let
security checks be a burden on your
software deployment Baracoa greenlight
gives you secure coding feedback in
seconds directly in your IDE try Verico
hood greenlight for eclipse free for 30
days and tap into vary codes binary
static analysis engine delivering
in-depth and accurate results to
developers in just seconds request your
trial of greenlight for eclipse today by
visiting vary code comm / greenlight -
trial not using eclipse visit Verico
comm / greenlight for information on
Visual Studio and IntelliJ plugins
thanks for listening to SE radio an
educational program brought to you by
Archer police software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SC - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com
you can also email us at team @ SC -
radio net this and all other episodes of
se radio is licensed under Creative
Commons license 2.5 thanks for listening